Hi, my name is Ksenia and I'm going to
tell you what's new
in sustainability
related to the EUDR certificate capture.
Why this matters? Because now it's like
people talking everywhere about this
EUDR, which is EU Deforestation
Regulation. It's starting to be
mandatory and now you really need to
track when you're getting to the EU
market your items,
where it was produced and that it has a
certification.
And usually it's tracked by batches
because some items can come from
one place, some from another one, some
can have certificates, some can have
something else.
So, that is why we are going to use the
item tracking
for that functionality. So, what we are
going to do? We are going to capture
EUDR relevant
items.
So, we will have on the item card the
dedicated fields, which will help you to
clarify which items are EUDR related,
which are not. Also, you will be able to
choose the commodity classification.
And as I mentioned, it will be necessary
to use item tracking for those items.
So, on the item card, on the
sustainability tab, you will have the
EUDR fields, EUDR relevant and EUDR
commodity.
Then, the all details about the
certificate itself will live on the lot
no information card.
So, if you have the EUDR relevant item,
then this tab will be visible for you
and you will be able to fulfill the
information such as certificate number,
certification schema. By the way, here
you can also use it for FSC, for
example, or something similar. You can
also track the dates and also use
it to copy and paste into those fields
the DDS information. And also it will
take the country.
For the purchase documents
for the purchase orders and receipts, we
added on the line level
EUTR flag.
Why we did it? So it would be easier for
the supply chain to define those lines
which are related to EUTR. So those
items will be easier to catch when
you're working in your purchase orders.
And one more
addition.
When you will do your sales invoices,
you can also inform customer that it was
certified and you can
show it on the layout. So it will be
possible to print out which lot it was
and also it will take the schema and the
certification number.
Okay, now let's summarize what we have
and what we don't have for now for the
EUTR.
So now you can link the relevant
information to your item cards. You can
use the item tracking for the tracking
and um
keep the information in the system and
track easily which orders had those
batches, which didn't. You can also
inform the customer with printing it on
the invoice.
Um but for now, I need to mark it. We
don't have the integration with Traces.
So the DDS numbers you will need to type
in
manually.
Uh
same for the geolocation.
But, we are continue to work on that
functionality. Uh for the feedback,
uh we will be happy if you will contact
us through the Viva Engage uh and um
share with us uh what is your
experience, what are the troubles,
which news you have from your customers.
Uh so, we can improve it and make it
work for everyone.
Thank you for watching. See you.